it's you versus Sean and like yeah
exactly right here just take the L like
50 of the time I did thank you thank you
very much let's move on
[Music]
[Applause]
okay round two Electric Boogaloo all
right
all right cool well all right should we
start from like yeah let's start from
zero just for context we just recorded
the intro to this and then Sean's fly
was open the whole time
okay with them all you know no okay all
right let me let me reintroduce the
scenario so
okay
yeah I'll say all right this is shot
okay this is Sean yo is that the right
yeah so Sean works at Acid note acid
note is an attack surface management
tool ASM yep uh I'll let you introduce
sort of the background and how it became
a thing and and sort of what spurred it
all and go just go ahead show yeah so
ASM or attack service managers like two
big pieces one is reconnaissance uh
which is understanding what your tax
service is uh from our perspective
that's mapping out what is publicly
facing so what can we see from the
internet what DNS data do you have what
IP ranges do you have and then more
Nuance than that is things that you
don't know what you have so like what
surrounding on the internet that we can
attribute to you so it's like it might
be random IP addresses that have TLS
sets that point back to you right um or
like what we what we consider like Cloud
assets that you don't like don't
typically fall under what you can
typically classify but we have our
heuristics to figure out this still
belongs to and it's still important so
that's the discovery piece of
understanding like what's there and then
the part I think we do really well at is
the security piece which is now
delivering value on top of what your
attack surface is finding what bugs do
you have telling you that these bugs are
still there and checking that
continuously
um so we will be setting not necessarily
the same amount of traffic but we do a
lot of validation for very high signal
bugs yeah and I think a lot of the value
people find out of our platform is that
when we send you an email saying we
found something it means that one is as
exploitable and two you need to fix it
yeah so you know we ignore all the
[__] we skip all the TLs findings
The Cypher Suites like we only tell you
that you know you have an ssrf on your
attack surface you've found the exploit
for it fix this or you have a like
exploitable version of Tablet running we
can validate the rce here's the like is
the payload and the response for it a
lot of the value comes from the high
signal and the reliability from how much
coverage we get yeah and and I guess
just to add a little bit more context to
that like we say Sean works for us you
know but actually Sean built asinos
yeah yeah Sean and chubs were were the
yeah initial programmers of this this
tool yeah so the Genesis of it was very
much like we wanted to capture all this
amazing stuff that shops already was
doing like he was doing this
yeah oh and he was he had this amazing
pipeline where he was constantly
discovering new assets on
um targets he was getting notified on
them and then automatically running his
own tool set across these targets right
right but then it's grown so much more
than that and I think in this process
there's a lot of things that you think's
like oh it's pretty easy to just
translate from dog values
no but you learn so so much more about
like it's a big difference from having
something like oh I need this to run you
know once a day or once a week or once a
life or something to having this run
every hour with an SLA and a customer
being able to run queries against their
data set that might be hundreds of
gigabytes large oh my God whenever they
want for however much of data they want
and like getting getting from like you
know bash groups and Python scripts
right to Reliable production code is
did you did you know what you're getting
yourself into here when you signed up
for this like I signed up to write like
tiny girl program right yeah I remember
I was in Union I'd get messages from
Charles you're like I need you to help
me write this thing and I'm like okay
sure I'll write you a signature scanner
like what do you need to support it's
like oh we just need to send some
requests and I'm like okay that's easy
enough so like one signature scanner
later we can send like you know 80 000
requests a second all right gosh dude um
but now you have a different problem
it's like all right well how do we run
this and it's like we can't just have
this ddosing people constantly right
right I mean it's not even ddosing it's
just one awesome
so there's there's a whole bunch of like
architectural learning we had where it's
just like as we've sort of grown we've
realized that you know we went through
the phase of let's just run everything
on one instance to okay now we need to
start like splitting up our services yes
not everything will scale the same way
right and it's like okay let me pause
you there present because that that's
kind of where we want to go with that
right it's like where I was kind of
thinking we could we could go with this
episode is kind of pick your brain for
the bug bounty hunters out there like
what kind of architectural decisions
would you recommend having having sorted
all of this you know for the past five
years of your life have it having lived
you know building this to scale having
lived you know
um going from the bug Bounty phase to
the full-fledged enterprise software
great you know
um where would you start what would you
do what a design to take decisions would
you make
um I know that that's a really vague
question but we can start with this we
were talking about message Brokers
earlier today yeah and can you talk a
little bit about message Brokers what
kind of role they play in this
architecture yeah and why you suggest
what you suggest so okay I guess the
first question is like what is a message
book and why do people use them right
yeah like there's kind of two ways of
doing things uh when you're trying to
automate things and build a launch
system yeah the first thing is you can
do things synchronously so it's like I
want you to you know give me all the sub
domains and scan them so you're just
like run a script that gets all the sub
domains and run a script that scans all
of them right that's okay yeah
sequentially that's okay when you have
like one set of things to do but when
you want to be like I want to see this
every hour on the hour and have like
hundreds of thousands or millions of
hosts to do you're gonna have very very
long running scripts and you're probably
like you know for a hundred thousand or
a thousand hosts you can probably run it
in one script and get it done in an owl
yeah but when you enter the phase of
like Millions tens of millions hundreds
of millions of posts which does happen
in bug bounty we we've I've run scripts
that were that were against three
million hosts yeah in the bug Bounty
programs that I have access to yeah and
like you might have heard of things like
Axiom that'll help you paralyze these
things yeah that's fine but at the end
of the day you're still like you run
them and then you collect them and then
that's kind of it yeah when you move to
the room of like I want just having
start having things like pipelines uh
then you will start venturing to a lot
of things like rabbit and Q right um or
like Amazon sqs all of these different
like queuing services and that's kind of
what message Brokers are it's a way of
queuing up a whole bunch of things uh
with what we call producers and then you
have a whole bunch of services or like
programs that start taking things off
this queue and consuming them hence
consumers
um and that's sort of the role the
message broker feels okay so the message
broker is you have various pieces that
you want to work asynchronously so
you've got let's say you've got your
subdomain tool and every time it finds a
subdomain it like pushes a message out
to the message broker and that message
gets sent out to the other microservice
that's going to do scanning and it gets
sent to another microservice that's
going to do you know it's going to pull
the TLs certain another one that's going
to like pull the HTML right is that
that's the idea right okay so yeah it's
pretty much like it's the glue yeah it's
kind of like the glue or the way I don't
get messages around yeah it's the moment
you put a letter in the mail mailman
decides you know yeah well all right
it's not quite that but it's more
generic than that yeah but yeah it's
pretty much the idea like you know you
Chuck the mail in the principle of that
yes you're sending a letter out and then
many people will receive that same
letter that's where it varies Joel you
know the rule we don't do live analogies
here on critical we're doing podcasts
ignore that every time don't laugh
Mariah my wife's over there laughing
because I suck at analogy no every time
I try to do an analogy live on the bot
it's terrible but yeah Okay so we've got
these message Brokers they're they're
Fanning out you know sister or the
messages to all the different pieces or
you know I guess we return talking a
little bit earlier today about event
driven sort of architecture yeah which
is not necessarily different from that
but is I guess more different at a
conceptual level than a yeah yeah so
event-driven architectures and part of
me if I'm wrong
um but generally the idea is there's
sort of two ways this organically grows
out one way is this and very much if
you're doing your own thing will sort of
fall into the first category as opposed
to the ladder sure the first category is
like ah I've got these things I want to
do so I want to get TLS so it's I want
to do a port scam I want to get a HTTP
title right so you have ideas of
processes or programs you want to run so
then you sort of build out your cues
um or whatever your like message broker
partitions however you want to call them
based off these tasks and you say like
I'll have one queue for TLS so that's
I'll have one queue for ports one queue
for titles
um and the outcome of that is pretty
much almost each service you think of
will eventually have liquid by itself
um but I think the other way is event
driven architectures where you very very
much think about what kind of daughter
am I working with right it's like I'm
working with sub domains I'm working
with IP addresses so you start flipping
the model and thinking that when I
discover an IP address then now I can
start informing things like I want to
start a TLS scanner I want to start
getting titles from it um and it's a
very it's a slight Nuance right because
you're no longer thinking about like
what am I trying to do but it's so much
more what do I have or what is already
happening yes what is happening and then
what do I want to do from those events
that occur okay um so an example of that
you know and that we were talking about
earlier today is like let's say we have
a um you know I guess we could say SLA
but it's not really that in our big
Bounty context let's say we have a
desire to to
um have an updated picture of DNS on all
of our assets every five minutes right
yeah you know when when that five minute
or when even that four minute 45 second
you know Mark comes around we can
trigger an event that expires our
current DNS
um representation and that and that that
event can trigger various different
activities is that is that how I'm
understanding it yep so I mean you can
go one way of like saying when things
expire usually will be things that
happen so you might say every every five
minutes you'll do a DNS resolution of
all your assets okay right and then oh
that and that's an event yes so the
event would be like we've discovered
this uh this sub domain maps to this DNS
record okay and that's the event right
right and then now like part of that
event the data you have is a sub domain
and IP address okay right so how do you
stop the the subscriber services from
basically just becoming bottlenecks
themselves because you have like one
thing doing one thing but it may need to
do a lot of work for to do that right so
like say you have one thing that's doing
the DNS resolution another thing that's
doing title getting the HTTP titles and
so on right what DNS resolution might
take significantly longer yeah and so
one of those things may be bottlenecks
just because it's going to take long how
do you get around that um there's a
couple ways I mean one is you can grow
faster and like well a lot of time that
we've spent
um at least in the couple years I've
worked is you have site heavily
optimizing for these things right you
realize that detecting Technologies is
taking like you know 30 seconds to a
minute per website right that's forever
right so you start optimizing that
aggressively can I get 60 seconds down
to 30 to 20 to 10. at some point you are
bottlenecked by the technical
limitations right but once you get to
that point and say okay now I'm already
six times fast now that seems better but
then the other side is sort of what
you're leading to is now scaling upwards
right you can start partitioning your
work into smaller pieces instead of
resolving all 300 million DNS records
you have at once you start shutting them
up and say like each I'll have multiple
workers starting to create events yeah
right
um I'll start scaling these out
parallelizing them creating replicas our
Axiom sh or whatever the website is for
it
um and then now you can have you know
300 workers each resolving a million at
a time right and then as you sort of
create all of these shots now you sort
of get over these issues of throughput
okay yeah the other side is you sort of
can do architectural decisions with the
tools so instead of just having one big
bulk result in one big block of data is
you start streaming the results out so
it's more like it the tool in itself is
also asynchronous yeah and then you have
a continuous stream of things but
depending on the scale you kind of don't
really need to make all these
optimizations yes yeah so I was actually
just about to add that like so this
episode and I think the lessons that
we're learning here from Sean this is
him doing this at an Enterprise grade
scale and for like we talked about on on
the Pod before like a lot of bug Bounty
stuff is literally just duct taped
together with like crazy nuclei scripts
so don't yes yeah don't feel like you
have to do this unless you want to
unless it's your thing to like write
cool do you disagree with that you're
looking you're making a face I make the
face because I think it's something
because you do that [__] is that why
wait yes it is because I've lost Sean's
Recon scripts before I mean speed I'm an
engineered because that's my day job my
job is to build this for the Enterprise
I beat you in DNS Recon because I need
you quicker for work yeah um but I think
if you're if you're one person doing
this by like I have a team of people
supporting me right when I say like I
build a service that shards it up runs
asynchronously across a message broker I
have a team of two incredible like
infrastructure Engineers that maintain
like I don't know 6
I have a team of five Engineers that
help me build software to do all of this
mind you I don't use asset known for bug
vouchers right like right Enterprise
because this is an Enterprise but when
I'm talking about these problems we're
having they're very much similar to what
you see in the bug Bounty space yeah and
I think when people say that you can't
scale Beyond this or like this tool
doesn't do this I think that's a
limitation of time and effort not a
limitation of the tool wow I think you
can solve technical problems of like oh
you can't scan this fast or you don't
have this data yeah you just need to be
able to invest the time and energy into
it yeah that's one of the things I
really like about talking to you too is
like like we I feel like the question
for me A lot of times is like all right
well you know this isn't moving fast
enough so I'm going to scale outward and
just but and then you see you you know
you bring a refreshing perspective but
what if you tuned math scan to actually
just be able to go you know six or seven
times faster and then that just solves
all your issues magically and and you
know it's not as necessarily a different
it's even more intriguing to be able to
dive deeper into those problems because
in order to tune it you have to
understand it at a lower level too which
I think Fosters a lot of growth as a as
a hacker if you do that it's a very very
different skill set though yeah it is
and I think it's but I also think that's
like a really good way to look at it
because like if you think about it right
if you have like a really inefficient
system instead of just multiplying that
system to try and make it more efficient
optimize the system and then see if you
need to multiply it because you're going
to have cost savings you're going to
have scaling savings like it it's it's
it like that lack of multiplication is
going to save you in so many other areas
where instead of having to like use an
inefficient system multiple times in a
row to uh to like compensate for the
lack of optimization you can just solve
that by optimizing and spend a little
more time doing that instead yeah it
feels so good too you know when you get
something optimized like I did this once
right I I rewrote all of my other stuff
is like garbage like it's python taped
together you know python 2
um but this one time I was like you know
what I I don't know why I fixated on
this problem so much but I literally was
like all right you know what aqua tone
it takes a picture of the you know the
website and then it downloads the TLs
cert and I was like you know what I want
to do that in one TCP connection yeah
and and because it was making two TCP
connections and I was like for some
reason that day it was like killing me
yeah so I like wrote this whole thing
with chrome devtools protocol to like
grab the TLs certificate from chrome
devtools protocol and then also take the
screenshot at the same time and it was
not that much faster and if it but I
felt great it should be like 2x right
yeah it's like you know it wasn't even
that I mean it was I mean you'll find
anything involving Chrome is this black
box of time and effort oh yeah we've
spent
months because we like the only way you
really can do proper technology
detection is you need to evaluate
JavaScript right right and there's been
all of these solutions to try to get
around it but I do them today you kind
of need to run a browser yeah and we've
spent countless hours trying to shoehorn
existing Solutions into an Enterprise
context at some point we're just like
[__] it yeah just rewrite it yeah yeah
and do you ever draw that line where
you're like this isn't worth the time
and effort or or is the juice kind of
always worth the squeeze
um we always start with the simplest
solution and almost everything that
we've implemented will start with what
can we do that gets us 80 of the way
there with 20 of the effort like as the
note started as Python scripts around
existing tools and then as we sort of
yeah that's that's the origins yeah yeah
anybody who automates does that I think
like if you're doing it yourself that's
100 where you should start and you
should not start from an event-driven
architecture or like a auto scaling
kubernetes system yeah you should start
from janky Python scripts that do yeah
that automate what you're doing now okay
um into something quicker have you ever
seen that XKCD about automation oh I
love that taste okay we'll put it up on
the screen but but basically there's
this XKCD graph what's the timestamp I'm
gonna I'm gonna have to write that down
so we don't forget okay all right okay
so yeah so basically there's this XKCD
graph right it's like what people think
automation's gonna do and it's like oh
you know you do a little bit of
automation slow you down a little bit
and then you exponentially get past and
in reality what happens is it gets a
little bit faster and then you lose all
of your productivity trying to maintain
yeah and trying to make it better and
like you spend so much more time fixing
and working on the tool than you ever
spent like actually getting the benefits
from the automation yeah and I think
that's like perfectly exemplified by
what you just said because it like it's
so easy to fall into that trap where
you're like hmm I really need to do this
perfectly I need to like build the best
fastest way to do simple task a right
and instead you should just being be
like
uh there's This Acronym k-i-s-s keep it
simple stupid right and just keep it
simple just
eighty percent of the work uh 80 of the
result 20 of the effort right it's just
like so much easier to start from there
and then reevaluate and iterate on where
you're at oh okay and just like iterate
iterate iterate iterate until you're hit
you hit a wall and then iterate again
and then I think the best results I've
gotten from all the automation stuff was
not actually spending time planning out
a whole architecture was just running it
in every week sitting down like for one
day that week and asking like why like
has this been effective enough this week
um and I think we got a period where we
were competing on some takeovers right
yes we did yes and it would go back and
forth every other week of seeing like
who is getting more takeovers or right
whatever
um and the process literally was like
every week I'd ask myself has this
week's yield been sufficient or do I
need to spend time making it better
right and the weeks that I made the most
progress in making of battle is when I
had the lowest yield because there's no
better motivator for you to make
something than knowing Justice getting
loaded
nobody else is making your money yeah
yeah so how do you how do you evaluate
like at an Enterprise level when you're
trying to optimize what are you doing to
figure out where those pitfalls are
within your application right how do you
analyze that right and so so you know
we've we've done our disclaimers now we
get the real real reason we have them
here which is for you freaks that love
to code love to optimize and want to be
you know win your your Bounties in bug
Bounty by being the fastest and over
optimizing
voila here we go so yeah okay it's a
very different scale when you're
operating uh across so to explain a bit
like okay to not disclose our entire
architecture
at a high level we scale out our
services across hundreds of replicas
across hundreds of ec2 instances right
um and
profiling and I guess observing the data
there is very different from running
something on one machine so in our case
of like me writing my own stuff
um I would just have one ec2 instance
it's writing this one program that does
you know whatever takeovers they're
doing right right in that case it's
pretty straightforward I can just attach
a profiler use the inbuilt golang
profiler and start looking at okay
where's time being spent how am I using
it Etc right and just do some basic
programmatic optimization okay so I'm
going to pause you there because I've
never done that
um so essentially what what you're using
and of course you just attach the basic
profiler no and I just I I so the
profiler is something that tells you
what operations are taking the longest
in your code execution or yeah so what a
profiler does is that it records what's
happening in your program okay um with a
small amount of overhead I think golang
is probably the role of like five to ten
percent at worst I think now it's in the
wrong one to two percent that's awesome
that's great so effectively what it does
is it sort of takes a whole bunch of
snapshots every every millisecond or
every second it'll take like a whole
bunch of snapshots and ask like what is
running at this moment and then what you
do with this all these snapshots is you
aggregate them together and it tells you
at this point in time this function is
running and this function took seven
seconds to run right and you can start
seeing a heat map and they have all
these great tools I think there's a
great like flame graph profiler that
shows you exactly how long is this spent
in real function wow over a given period
of time
um and the value of that is that you
sort of start to very clearly see where
time is spent in your program am I
spending all that time waiting on a
network request you know that's the case
then maybe I can spend like more Network
more that network network requests at
the same time waiting sure right so you
can start paralyzed horizontally and
then you might start hitting a
bottleneck of oh I'm actually no longer
spending all my time waiting on network
requests I'm spending all my time in
these like three lines that is actually
just looping over all the stuff demands
really really fast for no reason uh all
right so maybe I can start skipping out
of that Loop or restructure it so I
don't need to Loop over that so many
times sure sure and you sort of slowly
start to understand why my program is
slow right yeah well I love I love that
actual data-driven approach there like
like for me I if I were to try to do
that same thing I would look at the code
I'd be like okay
that's their whole reason I think you
see there's a lot of engineer like pure
engineering companies is that like this
is very common practice yes where it's
just like you have a system that needs
to run at scale just due to user demands
yeah and
in order to make it work yeah you have
to figure out what where it's being slow
and make it better and optimize it just
to Simply function yeah whereas
it's almost like that but it's to like
another level where it's like yeah it
needs to function but also it needs to
be like the best right it needs to be
better than the best so how do you make
it better than the best I mean you know
if you want to go the next step after
them like at some point profile
industrial program isn't enough right
because like at some point you're gonna
start when you start doing a whole bunch
of networking stuff you start asking
questions like well how do I interact
with the network right and like the
obvious answer is okay you can make
Network faster right but this comes back
to like that question of what happens
when you type in google.com how many
layers deep do you want to go yeah dude
it's so funny you mentioned that because
we literally talk about that all the
time you know and it's it's literally
like uh that that comes having a core
understanding of how that works yeah is
just absolutely pivotal to everything
you know it's you have to understand
every single detail of that yeah there's
a great uh GitHub repo that goes over
like all the difference yeah it goes all
the way to like the key presses yeah
it's like an electrical signal it's fire
push the key down oh my God it's really
good we need that that's a amazing I've
never heard of that and I'm going to
text you right now but that's yeah
um back when I was in like University
that was like all the all the
interviewers yeah that were like you
know oh they're gonna ask you what
happens when you type Google like
google.com in a search bar and so like
you know that was something that you
would just like memorize yeah does DNS
look up and then yeah I feel so
validated right now because like I never
knew that anyone else like put as much
importance on that like that's where I
start with everything like and oh man
that's
I mean don't get me wrong you can go
verify the other direction of like over
optimizing for this yeah it kind of
depends on what you find fun like
sometimes I find fun in just doing all
of this stuff other times like you know
you probably should be hacking instead
of yeah exactly yeah but I can imagine
that it like asset notes scale even the
very very marginal optimizations are
gonna be super worth it because because
of the the scale that you're operating
on um so one of the common projects that
one of my Engineers is working on is
um one of the features and that we have
is integrating with like your cloud
services so integrating with AWS or
integrating with gcp
um and we've just onboarded a customer
that start pulling assets in yes so like
we ingest all that data we help enrich
it give you extra information and then
that sort of feeds into the whole
platform though sure
um one of my Engineers is currently
working very closely with the customer
because they've initially when we built
this feature we're like okay
approximately what scale can we handle
and a big question that sort of you
mentioned a data-driven decision making
right is like understanding what what
performance properties are we looking
for when we build this what are our
expectations what can we handle a
customer came in and we're like okay we
set a reasonably High number it's like
10 times more than whatever and our
customers are doing sure they came in
and onboarded with 10 times more than
that oh no you're joking there's no way
I spoke to them and they're like yeah it
turns out AWS had an internal limit and
we had to ask AWS to bump that oh my
gosh dude you can't even rely on my AWS
limits so we estimated pretty good right
like we estimated to what aws's maximum
public limit was sure sure they're above
that by another order of magnitude wow
dude so his spent the past few weeks
optimizing our service for synchronizing
this it
an inordinate amount like yeah our
average expectation is we should be in
sync with you every five minutes yeah
right it's such a that's a good that's a
good expectation optimizing this 90 got
us down to like 10 minutes right wow and
when you already optimized it 90 to get
another 50 on top it's huge yeah it is
very challenging unbelievable amount of
optimize it like yeah work to get there
and now you're looking at just like well
what is all the micro optimizations can
we be doing can we be like not making
requests for things that we don't need
can we be turning off requests that we
know are immediately going to fail can
we start pre-caching requests this is
the second entire set of limits we
didn't realize existed on assuming role
between AWS accounts
all right recorder died yep jump back in
all right so jumping back I guess we
needed to get back on track anyway so
all right so bringing this back to the
discussion surrounding if you were gonna
oh
that's spicy
Final Destination what the heck did you
think that was what that was all right
all right so
um yeah
the
ghosts are not happy that we're
revealing the optimization Secrets right
now oh my gosh
um okay so so Mike Mike died we're
getting back to back to the topic here
um yeah so just bringing it back around
we want to try to bring it back to bug
Bounty and and get some architectural
wisdom on this so we already talked a
little bit about message Brokers and the
role that they play and using that in
order to
um build an architecture that allows all
these different microservices which
perform all the different tasks like
performing scanning and
um
and you know DNS resolutions and you
know volume scanning all that those
those get sort of sent and connected by
the message broker
um what kind of message Brokers would
you recommend and what other pieces of
the stack would you recommend that it
would save us a headache
um that you've learned over your years
of engineering this sort of thing it
depends on how much time and money you
have right I think
a lot of things you'll see is like sqs
uh rather than cure yeah I think those
are okay Solutions if you need something
now actually I wouldn't recommend
rabbitmg yeah don't don't do rabbit the
reason being is very difficult to keep
alive and then once you start getting to
a certain scale there's an excellent
blog post I need to dig it up somewhere
I might link it to you yeah where it
says don't use your message broker as a
database right yeah yeah that's the idea
being that if a message is sitting in
your message broker for too long
um then now you actually are just using
your message work as a database instead
which you shouldn't be doing the idea is
that your message workers where you
queue things up and then those things
get consumed So eventually you should
try to get to zero so what uh what do
you use to sort those messages if when
they're in the queue so we do use the
queue but the idea is that you should
have enough processes to make sure your
queue is being consumed okay right and
if you're saying that your queue is
already going up
um or what I recommend is like for a
message broker like Nats which I think
is a great piece of software for this
because relatively lightweight it's got
a whole bunch of different sdks for you
to implement against and and relatively
n-a-t-s yes Nats it's pretty good for
this and there's a whole bunch of other
projects adjacent to it that help it
um for example things like kedoc k-e-d-a
okay so if you are using kubernetes this
is a great way to scale it
um so nuts is a great solution you might
also have like things like redis the
only difficult with redis is that uh
it's very hard to get good visibility
into it oh really
um so that's very important if you're
asking questions like how long has the
message been there or when should my
messages be expiring redis may not be
the best solution because you need a
whole bunch of other things to manage
that for you right this is really good
at what it does which is be a key value
store and give you really accurate
results really quickly right um but for
something that you actually want to use
as a message broker things like nuts
have a whole bunch more features saying
things like I want to expire messages
that are there for more than 24 hours
yeah man that would be clutch because if
you even if you do get a system clogged
up right yes you want to have some way
of making sure it doesn't dos the rest
of your node exactly right like you need
to have all of this the problem I was
having with rabbitmq yes right it will
run up all your storage and then ship my
disks for my systems down or it'll run
up guys yeah goodbye all my messages
goodbye everything else that's running
yeah um so you do want to set yourself
some limits understand that okay I want
the maximum capacity to be one gigabyte
of memory I want the maximum disk space
user to be 15 gigs sure I want the
maximum age of my messages to be 24
hours and if things are taking more than
that then I've got a problem with my
code yeah it's not a problem with the
message broker right so there's that
piece to it and and one of the things
that I learned from the message broker
era was like you know when I was working
with it was you really want to make sure
that you're consuming at a faster rate
than you're getting things published
into right like you know you alluded to
that earlier that you know it needs to
hit zero and and even when you've got a
bunch of data coming into your pipeline
like as long as you're consuming
you're adding to it yeah it should be
going down and that's what you want to
see I'm of course it can have spikes
right because naturally some things will
have more spiky and like what do they
call seasonal Trends than others sure
sure but yes you should be aiming
towards at some point it should be able
to hit zero and if it never hits zero
then now you have a question of why
isn't all hitting zero is something
taking too long or I'm not scaling it
out at night and then we go back to
optimization yeah right yeah okay so we
got Nats and
is great for scaling but it's mostly
kubernetes relevant okay and if you're
finding something yourself probably
don't use kubernetes right I have a team
of people I mean at one point it was
just me managing a lot of kubernetes
yeah I'm sure that was fun
cluster for my microservices when I was
doing this this architecture and it was
a lot of it was a lot of problems you
know and and I think um you know one
thing that we talked about earlier was
like trying to run mascan or any really
performant
scanning from within a container is just
not going to happen right there's
there's a whole bunch of condo training
you need to do to make that work okay um
so one of the most common problems
you'll get is you'll get what they call
a contract limit okay um and what a
contract limit is is pretty much when
you're making connections
um on your operating system
um what your kernel needs to do is be
able to track what packets going out and
coming back actually belong to us right
right like your kernel doesn't want when
I send out a web request for google.com
for journals to start sending me traffic
and then intercept my google.com request
and then poison that right in theory you
know yeah
um so what they do is they track all the
IP ports combinations going in and out
yeah and things that are not relevant
they just drop right right and that's
what they call a contract and there's a
big table that tracks all of this uh
well the contract limit is is that this
table couldn't fill up and this is very
this is very like likely to happen with
Port scanning because what are you doing
you're just spanning a bunch of you're
spending a bunch of IP addresses and
ports which are the two things that
contract tables rely on right right and
when you're doing it across millions of
hosts across tens of thousands of IP
addresses your table is going to be
formed really really quickly and is that
contract table at a host level or a
container level
um so depending on how the networking
you have is set up
um if you're using like kubernetes level
normal container networking you'll have
two different IP address spaces right
you have the Pod IP address space and
then you also have your nodes IP address
or the instances IP address sure and
then now you need a translation layer of
when a web request goes from the pot
when a packet goes from the Pod to the
instance and then out to the internet
now you need to trap translate that Nat
back into the Pod
um and if you're not sure what I'm
talking about uh Network address
translation allows you to have multiple
IP addresses behind the big IP address
right that's how your router gives you
an IP that is not connected to the
public internet yes
um and in kubernetes it's kind of the
same thing your pods need to get an IP
address that's not connected to the
public IP address so so they have that
translation as well so this actually
happens on account of the instance and
that means that when you're from a pod
flooding the internet with a whole bunch
of packets that means that these are all
being translated by your kernel between
the pods IP space and the instances IP
space and then at another level if
you're using something like AWS there's
another one for AWS translating between
your private IPS space and the public IP
address of the internet
um and each one of those is its own
bottleneck right and you'll often see
and you probably hit this very often if
you try to mask again suddenly your
connections start dropping you
everything's just disappears yes and
it's like it's super unreliable what's
going on it's because of this so what do
you do you move container networking
from the Pod to privileged networking
bad for security good for performance
sure right so you get rid of one layer
of this then the second part is you move
your instance away from any sort of
netting from like private IP ranges to
public you just slam it directly onto
the public internet okay right and then
that means that there's no sort of
bottlenecks between you and the internet
unless you've got like an ISP level CG
Maps sure which is where your ISP itself
does more than adding so maybe you ask
them can I disable CG now opt out or
find a difference it's absolutely like
one of the reasons why I so value these
conversations with you is like do you
know how long it would take you to get
to that level where you understand each
one of those steps about you know the
contract table and and the kernel
optimizations and then all this various
level of natting and like it's because
you have been at war with these problems
for the past five years oh yeah and man
it's just such a pleasure to be able to
to sit down and Skip all of that
um and so yeah that's great so you solve
that by by putting it on you know
outside of the kubernetes cluster
putting it directly on onto a a box
that's on the internet as little not as
possible as little bottlenecks as
possible and then you can do more
efficient scanning outlay and then
publish it back into the the message
broker or you know I guess that well
this is another question this is a
little bit of a uh I don't know what we
won't go too far down this rabbit hole
but what the problem that I had with my
my message perfect structure was I um I
had a I had a cue that was right reflect
this data to the database yep right and
that one always had a bottleneck yeah
but and all you know all these things
would be throwing it into that queue
yeah and that queue would be trying to
update the database like 50 bajillion
times a second and I those those
messages would always get kind of stuck
there and then it would everything would
be a part so you sort of realized that
like storing it out of a system needs a
whole different set of problems that's
why dbas and databases administrators
was like its own role for all of these
decades and it still is because it's a
very relevant position yeah what you
find in that situation is now you're in
the role of like database optimization
not in program optimization well I was
also using mongodb rather than anything
like you know so how to be fair is quite
performance yes mongodb's web scale yeah
oh my god dude I forgot about that
DPS web scale yeah you should put a link
to it yeah
we're gonna link that that's great like
mongodb is great uh but you also have to
understand your access patterns and your
data patterns right right like sorry
I'm sorry continue
so yeah you need to understand your
access like your both your read and
write patterns and I'm assuming in your
case you probably structures like oh I
have an IP address that is sort of what
the key is and then I have all the
metadata is like bars literally yes
um and it's kind of good in the sense
that it's very simple and it's great for
your querying but it's probably not the
best for writing because you're doing a
whole bunch of updates to the same Keys
yeah exactly right and you find that
um not all databases handle that really
well and also depending on where your
database is hosted and how it's being
managed that's its own set of problems
right you'll find with databases you're
never really Bound by networking you're
very much Bound by disk read speed
memory bandwidth
um how big your caches are that kind of
stuff yeah and so and this is the DB
itself and the size of it's DB yeah and
and and so I guess I went with [__] in
that scenario but I see most of the
people are going with post postgres and
and so you know what do you think about
that architectural decision what other
you know what was the reasoning what
about nosql databases versus SQL
database when it comes to like and I I
think the model itself of of just sort
of Recon data in general lends itself a
little bit better to a highly relational
you know database and and you know where
you can draw Matt easily draw Maps
between all of these different objects
and have them broken out rather than in
like a single Json blob or something
like that
um so that's kind of where I went wrong
with that but I think like there's not
necessarily a right answer I know some
people want like graph databases as well
yeah um yeah that's a big that's big
yeah so I mean philosophy went for the
simple stupid option we picked postgres
for our architecture right there's some
other reasons for that mainly around how
it's being used because a lot of the
value customers have is like well we
want a query for data with these
property we want it to be in this part
of infrastructure tagged with this that
are online that have this port that have
this kind of title and all of these
relational elements is sort of how we
built on our schema and this is also
where nosql sucks it sucks so hard like
it's really really bad at that like
right it's like iterating over every
single document it's like oh yeah does
this match does this match does this
match does this match so yeah postgres
is great for.com asking those kinds of
questions I think
um dude I found out about indexes
changed my life index like and then I
started putting an index on everything
and then yeah I'm sure
I was like let me just index all the
things
that I've spent countless hours just
staring at postgres explains trying to
understand why queries are slow yeah you
have multiple phases of optimizing
postscripts sorry the first phase like
okay Chuck an index on it the next phase
is like okay do I look at start looking
at read replicas or do I start looking
at like better Hardware right right and
then it's like okay maybe I go with
better Hardware but now you start having
the problems like okay how do I get
around the problem that even with
indexes these queries are taking a long
time right so what do you do then well
maybe I start pre-computing Donna right
maybe I saw using things like pure like
serialized views right problems but then
it also creates its own problems right
because refreshing materialized views
has to happen frequent and obviously you
have recent data but then they also
consume its own database operations so I
mean at the end of the day engineering
is just a whole bunch of trade-offs
right it's like I have this much time
and this much effort and I have this
solution I want to get to how much time
and effort can I spend to get to the
best solution yeah no that that's that's
really well put in it and you know
you're never going to have a fully
optimized solution with no with no
trade-offs in that sort of situation
yeah it's it's I mean it's back to that
80 20 right it's like you start at 80 20
and then
maybe 90 tennis where you draw the line
because that last ten percent for the
extra 50 is just for a non-enterprise
use case it's just not worth like it
really isn't yeah like it's you versus
Sean and like yeah exactly right here
just take the L like 50 of the time I
did thank you thank you very much and
just move on that's exactly what I do
I'm not just going right exactly and
I'll just stay there with my takeovers
that was the strategy man that was the
strategy oh man um coming back to your
question in terms of yeah architecture
postgres is great I think you do need to
think a little bit about what your
schema looks like uh one Pitfall I
didn't realize until very late on is
postgres does really poorly when you can
like repeatedly update the same rows in
very very quick succession
and I think one of the things I would
like to have done going back is spent a
bit more time thinking about
like append only or write only tables
and like partitioning those up
interesting okay because you sort of
find that if you for example in a very
common Paradise like I have all these IP
addresses I'll just have a column that
says whether they're online or offline
right right and then maybe I'll add a
timestamp of when that happens right but
say you run a mask in every hour right
across all these IP addresses you're
effectively rewriting this entire table
every hour yeah right if even if you
don't update the true or false for
whether it's online offline if you
update the timestamp and say I last
updated this at this time
like the way postgres works is that when
you write a row unless you have what
they call Hot tuples which is on extra
space to do small roads
um it effectively deletes your row and
inserts a new one right really yes
that's how that's how postgres maintains
its uh asset properties of like when I
write something and I haven't finished
yet you don't read partially what I've
written right you have oh that's
interesting corrective view of the world
okay right so repeatedly updating the
same thing
um will just mean that you're deleting
the same row and adding a whole bunch of
times the way they solve this is what
they call vacuuming which is the cleanup
rows that have been deleted right so you
can write to them again
um but unless you sort of give the time
to do that
um if you're writing more then your
vacuum is keeping up with and there's a
whole bunch of vacuum tuning stuff that
they ask you to do then you're just
going to quickly grow it in space or
your indexes are going to become
something very inefficient because your
table is like what they call bloated
it's like every gigabyte of space might
only be 100 megabytes actually occupied
sure sure yeah postgres is great
um that being said depending on what
scale like if you're on a small scale
and your diverse is a couple of people
that's no one chance it doesn't matter
right but when you're operating like
hundreds of give your bytes terabytes of
data then you have very different
questions to answer yeah no for sure and
do you also find benefit like with a
write-only table or a pendant on the
table with having almost like a version
history essentially yeah like what's
going on over time like what's changed
over time uh that being said it also
does grow very very quickly so maybe you
might look at some solutions like click
house or what they call common enough
columnar I can't pronounce it the column
based database stores right and they
compressed data slightly differently
they're better for things like that
which is kind of like
I draw the analogy to iot because you're
kind of doing like the it use cases that
you use things like click house to
measure temperatures across the world
right and every second you're recording
a new temperature in the attitude is
database and they're very efficient at
storing that
um I think it's very similar to that
because instead of storing temperature
we're storing our things online right or
what's the status code of this sure
right across millions of things across
the world every hour right so sometimes
that might be a better use case uh but
it sort of comes with the Traders like
well how do I want to query this yeah am
I just interested in what is the latest
result or am I interested in Trends or
am I interested in slicing up my data
depending on which customer is asking
yeah well and and that's why we kind of
asked because in the beginning it might
be oh I really want to just like query
this from my command line but also at
some day you might want to look at
Trends you know okay how often are they
you know rotating these these IP
addresses how often are they yeah you
know or from a customer perspective like
when did this exactly change or or why
are we noticing the strange Behavior
like is it flipping on and off like and
we get that question so so many times
yeah
um so yeah I think like four guarantee
people I think it's a very different
question set and I think what you should
be optimizing for is not like there's
long term training use case it's what
information do I need right now and how
do I get there right and only once
you've done that then can you start
iterating on what schema works for your
use case sure I can't tell you what
schema is good because you don't have
five Engineers behind you building this
entire system and and you're not an
Enterprise application yes and yeah so
so I guess let's let's think about a use
case this is very simple
um what for example one of the things
that I I I and we were talking about
earlier today with uriyota was
um you know dividing out your domains
and your IP addresses logically and and
not making your your subdomain your
primary key right yeah like that was my
when I that was my biggest architectural
mistake I made when I built my review
system was I was like I was obsessed
with subdomains yeah like a sub domain
is the end-all BL but really at the end
of the day it all goes down to I you
know IP addresses I shouldn't say that
but it mostly all goes down by well I
mean that's a good point because I think
so this is the kind of discussion I want
to have is like you know what what are
those those mistakes like focusing on
subdomains instead of focusing IP
addresses as the lowest level of logical
entities and you know mapping those
because yeah I think it also comes to
like what kind of Recon are you doing
yeah and I think subdomains is fine
because a lot of things like sub-dimens
is the easiest identified way of looking
at something yeah the reason you say IP
addresses is relevant is because there's
a whole bunch of assets and like what we
yeah what we consider assets that might
not have a sub domain Associated right
right like companies like
or just something that you don't know
yeah yeah they don't like they exist on
the internet you just can't see them yet
it was also like a whole separate set of
pitfalls like when you start to go to
that level because IPS rotate like
things yeah sub domains get reassigned
so like you might have an IP address
that's stored and then you're scanning
you're like oh my God there's a new
service on this yeah it's exploitable
and it turns out it belongs to somebody
else like it's com it's not even theirs
and then you report it to the company
and they're like you know we don't own
this IP yeah yeah that's true I mean
yeah I think it all it all depends on
and this is kind of what we were talking
about earlier sort of correlation
factors and I think that could
definitely be a new logical entity in a
Recon structure system you know like
like you have this this domain and
you've got that you know database what
you know about that domain and you've
got this a subdomain meaning and or fqen
and then you've got this IP address and
then you've got some sort of
relationship between the two of them and
how that's correlated it could be a DNS
um an entry that correlates them it
could be a TLS you know Sni you know it
could be you know
um historical data it could be you know
what what else could it be I'm trying I
mean
modeling over this idea for a couple
years yeah tried to implement this at
astronaut but the use case is very
nuanced right yeah so yeah when you
start getting to more and more Cloud
native apps the ways you identify what
you consider like an asset starts to
change very differently yeah right in a
very traditional old school setting
it'll probably be like we have IP
addresses on servers and that's it we
might give them a sub domain but when
you get to like the other end of the
spectrum Uber starts writing Things
based on your subpar
um and if you want to be more specific
yeah Uber starts routing Things based on
your subpath in a specific geolocation
yeah right so even if you hit the same
IP address with the same sub domain same
Sni same path you'll be hitting two
different data centers that might be
running different versions of your app
yeah right that's true even further it
might be getting feature flagged and
routed to another version of the app
based on your user ID right and all of
these means that at the end of the day
the app you're looking at might not even
be the same one you might be getting
like a China version of The Uber app
versus a America version of The Uber app
sure or even you might be getting a beta
Uber app versus the production app right
and I think factoring all of these in
into like what you call this correlation
yeah probably as overkill for most
people
um yeah but I want it to be perfect
well how about this every single company
you create a unique correlation right
you build your mental model you grab
cosmen back and you ask him how to
deploy their apps right right and then
you work backwards from there you say I
factor it doesn't care about geolocation
they don't care about user ID they care
about their tenant ID they care about
their sub domain whatever but for Uber
totally different story now we're an
entire different Paradigm he's a new
correlation method right you want to go
to the nth degree you might as well I
mean you made a perfect point which is
that we can't
over it I mean you so perfectly pointed
out that that flaw of like this is just
gonna be way over engineering some of
these some of these things and and at
the end of the day you are gonna you are
gonna you know run into these these
scenarios where you're like ah it's not
perfect but then you gotta you gotta
decide is the trade-off of that fixing
that problem actually gonna get me
enough bounties to justify the time that
I'm spending on and they answered on to
that a lot of the time is no I mean
sometimes unless you want to make it
your thing yeah like sometimes they're
hacking around it right you might have
the system that works for 90 of the
cases and then you decide okay I'm gonna
spend like three weeks looking at Google
infrastructure right and now this is its
entire own base that has its own books
written on it right um so I'm just gonna
hack together something that's just for
this and maybe you'll find that I've now
spent three months on it I understand it
enough now I can merge it back into
Mainline and feed this across the rest
of it like you don't have to make
everything into your giant monolithic
Beast right you can always have smaller
pieces that's for something else and
then once you sort of figure how this
works it then comes back naturally into
the rest of the work you're doing yeah
wow yeah it's it's a you know I've like
you said I have retreated from my my
Recon world into my live hacking event
world and I've just been spending so
much time in the in the you know hands
on the keyboard manual hacking lately
that I forgot about all the horrendous
challenges that there are in the in the
because it really is an engineer it's a
it's an engineering problem it's an
engine it's a problem space like you
have to realize that like if you're
trying to tackle this problem
individually and you're running into
struggles and you're not an engineer
well that that's to be expected yeah
yeah it's gone like it's hard like
literally there are full-time Engineers
who spend all day every day trying to
solve this problem yeah there are teams
yeah teams yeah multiple teams of
Engineers who spend all day trying to
fix this problem and can't or have to
spend weeks years solving it right and
so like I think again like optimize what
you need to optimize for right like
think about your problems that think
about the context think about what data
do you need for what targets you're
focusing on and if you have to make an
optimization make an optimization if you
don't just don't do it you know what I
mean like get it where you need it to be
and then use it to its fullest and if
it's not enough then improve yeah or
hire a company of people and do it that
way yeah yeah just become acid note
exactly it's easy yeah so so I guess one
of the things that I wanted to bring up
as well just kind of in pursuit of the
Relentless return to deep technical
content
um can you give us some wisdom on how to
deal with DNS wild cards and what kind
of pitfalls we can uh avoid in that area
and for those of you that are not super
familiar with the concept well I let
Sean think for a second
um the concept is that some wild card
um some domains Facebook good example
Facebook
um Zoom also has it
um yeah there's a lot of wild cards and
essentially what that means is you can
put any random string at you know what
is it zoom.us or something
and it will resolve to an IP address yes
yeah it's basically anything that lets
you generate submits like Shopify like
store.myshopify.com or whatever like the
way that all of those route without them
creating new DNS entries is that they
have one catch-all DNS entry that's
right it's wild card and so basically
anything dot whatever resolves to like
the same set of IP addresses or the same
C names and then that gets routed like
yeah and so the big the biggest problem
with that is figuring out okay which one
of these is a wild card response which
is always going to be the same and has
no interesting data or which one of
these is unique and that's one of the
hardest problems well I mean the way we
solve it at work is very different for
how we solve it in bounties yeah when we
solve it at work we have access to your
AWS account so we don't need it yes
right um so we can save a whole bunch of
you know energy beautiful love that for
you
let me just ask for that exactly ID real
quick yeah like can you just give us
your DNS yeah but in the bug Bounty
space we we do it at resolve time like
we build our own custom resolver that
does all the like resolution checking
and it pretty much like does wild card
detection every layer right so at every
depth of this updating we start trying
to detect is this a wild card or not we
figure out right what what is what is
expected to be a wild card what isn't a
wild card and then
it kind of depends on what you're
optimizing for at that point are you
willing to resolve millions of attempts
to find that one or two records that is
true or not
um or do you just discard this entire
set and move on to the next which once
again those are both viable options I've
done both of those before and they both
result in great things one because you
you're you know if you do actually go
through the weeds it results in you
finding hosts that no one else finds
because they're not willing to dig
through the weeks but if you if you
don't and you ignore that whole thing
you save hours and hours and hours of
time that you would solving one of the
hardest problems that you run into
because at face value it's like the
simplest ways ignore it or look through
every single one yeah and it's like
neither of those options are super great
one's super tedious and the other leaves
a gap so it's only tedious when it's
slow
but if you hypothetically could resolve
millions of results a second yeah
hypothetically of course right then if
only there was a company that did that
yeah right exactly right you you don't
need to like have the trade-off right
just resolve millions of results a
second yeah so that goes back to the
optimization right too and and I want to
say I haven't looked at this code in a
really long time but I want to say when
I when I try to solve this problem and
actually try to be able to weed out all
the wild cards I actually
resolved the I resolved a certain
subdomain and then I I appended
something to it and can and resolved it
a couple times as well and compared the
result and so for every single entry
that I was doing I was resolving you
know three or four times so it was it
was growing you know linearly in that in
that capacity right and and it was and
it was also there there was that and
then there was another piece of it
um and you
this
yeah because and you can cache it a
little bit with saying okay I've already
sort of figured out whether this level
of the subdomain is a is a wild card or
not but then you run into scenarios
where you got like
um subdomain Dash everything wildcard
yeah right and then you're always it's
going to blow up your database again if
you if you do it so the answer to
everything in computer science is a hash
map
everything yeah all the wide cards for
every single level yeah and then now you
can just start matching against every
corresponding level and see how far you
get that's real yeah what a beautiful
structure I love it it's lovely man yeah
no no that is good advice though you
know so you're saying you know let's
just take Uber for example uber.com
test.uber.com okay at determined
test.uber.com is not a a you know and
then you know you got
abc.uber.com okay that's that is a wild
card and then you can continue to grow
as the subdomains change and you at some
point you will have already resolved
that or you can quickly resolve that and
you're good to go yeah okay
um we are getting the signal from our
manager right now that I just wanted to
wrap up this episode yes Sean dude
thanks for coming on man thank you for
letting us pick your brain we will we
will definitely have Sean on again
um we're gonna have to do it over Zoom
because yeah um
crazy critical thinking budget
um you got anything you wanna you wanna
shill to the people oh
uh yeah don't don't try to solve hard
problems if you don't have to yeah and
don't try to find hot bugs where you can
find easy ones yeah and where can they
find us in them yeah you can find asset
nerd at sms.com
you can find us on Twitter at I think
probably yeah
um and then you can find me at us or on
Twitter like at showing your Landing is
it is a Sean you know do we need to like
check that really quick or are you
feeling pretty confident about that I'm
not confident okay I only should post on
Twitter there's nothing we'll put it
down below don't worry okay okay there
we go all right that's around awesome
that's a wrap
foreign